952.200.6071 david@simmer.ooo

https://simmer.ooo



Profile

18 years of deep experience in design, development, leadership, and putting it all together. My design and development work has been indispensable to a variety of startups, established businesses, educational institutions and non-profits across the country. Looking for a position where I can cross disciplines, set direction, serve a purpose, and build something exciting.

Experience

Owner & Creative Developer, Simmer Inc - 2000-present

Full-stack developer, designer, project manager, and solopreneur. Orchestrating, designing, prototyping and building clever, good-looking things on the web and in print. Branding and identity design, responsive design, UX and UI consulting, user-friendly content management creation. Managed subcontractors. Consistently delivered multiple simultaneous projects on deadline and on budget.

Founding Partner, Qara Partners - 2017-present

Spearheading the creation of online products and managing in-house design & technology development for a QA/RA consulting firm. Branding for company formation, full-stack developer, designer, project manager, and technical lead. Developing and selling online products for 21 CFR 820 & ISO 13485 efforts.

Senior Technical Advisor, Nearest You – 2017

Provided technical and strategic advice to a rapidly-growing online brand locator startup.

Web Development & UX Partner, Good Work Group - 2015-present

Full-stack development, design, and technical consulting to assist Good Work Group in making a lasting, positive impact through strategy, creative ideation, storytelling, design, and passion for worthy clients. Participated in project pitches, landed large-budget work, and managed client communication and meetings.

CTO, Medgineering Inc - 2014-2017

Architected, designed, developed, and deployed quality and regulatory-focused online consultant marketplace. Singlehandedly built a public MVP, getting us to revenue-positive immediately after launch. Rearchitected v2 on a Rails/Postgres/Dokku stack with async notifications and test coverage, laying the groundwork for additional developers to join the team. Familiarized myself with 21 CFR 820 & ISO 13485 to tailor v2 for the needs of quality/ regulatory clients and consultants. Created and managed branding and communications across our sales and support efforts. Sold the company in 2017.

Web Developer, Spring – 2013-2015

Provided high-performance front end development for various high-profile agency clients and brands. Worked remotely in sync with team members across the Atlantic. My very first project with Spring won accolades for its design and technical aspects.

Product Application Developer, Holmes Corporation - 2008-2015

Designer and developer on a small Agile-based software dev team. Designed and built online educational software on a custom Dojo and Python-based framework, working daily with backend developers, project managers, and marketing/sales staff to support and enhance learning products used daily by thousands of professionals. Kanban workflow, modified Scrum, automated testing with Selenium, continuous integration and deployment with Jenkins, BDD/TDD. Redesigned the company's own website, and produced several custom-themed Magento setups in cooperation with the IT and marketing teams.

Digital Technology Specialist, Normandale Community College – 2000-2004

Associate webmaster, responsible for new online initiatives, regular website maintenance and upgrades. Also provided video production, print design, photography and technology help desk staffing. Redesigned the entire college's web platform, building a complete permissions-enabled CMS (content management system) from scratch, reducing data entry time for academic and marketing departments by 67%.

Education

I switched careers at an early age, which made my educational track irrelevant! Happy to tell the story if you'd like to hear it. I'm largely self-taught in this field, and of course leveled up on the shoulders of the community

Skills

I'm very much full-stack: branding, design, UX, HTML, CSS, JS, Rails, PHP, Node, CMSs, databases, servers, you name it. If I haven't yet worked with a particular element of your stack, I'll be able to rapidly pick it up. Let's talk about what you're working with.

References

Delighted to provide references upon request.